to 23.
And we'll have the implications to pass the first
Christmas to Frank Flesch.
Please pray with me.
Finally, God, we love you.
God, we are so grateful for the chance to be a part of this community to be leaders in it.
We're thankful for those who are on the board and the decisions that they make.
God, I just pray that we would see the blessings that you've given us.
God, open our eyes to the way that you are blessed in our community.
And I just pray that we would appreciate that and do everything we can to continue that.
God, give wisdom, give unity, and just allow this to be a productive time tonight.
Father, and everything we do, we want to be more like Jesus.
Help us to do that.
It's business and then we pray.
Amen.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America.
And do that.
Look for which it stands.
One nation.
There you are.
And you're visible.
With liberty and justice are all.
Number four.
Public input.
Let's go to the personal appearances.
We have one Mr. Brian McLean.
And Brian, I'll before you get started.
You haven't been here before to do this.
But you get three minutes.
There'll be a timer on the screen.
I believe.
Right.
And the council cannot respond to you during this three minutes.
But at the end we'll have the appropriate department head.
See you tonight.
Everybody's respond to your response.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate the opportunity to be able to talk to you.
In 1989, January.
Service was began in 93 Northwest.
I am a commoner named Kim Highly.
That was her main name.
A couple months later after marriage,
we began residing in the home.
The electricity had been paid for the last 34 years and 10 months without fail in a timely manner.
November 30th.
On Friday, our Thursday, the electricity was cut off of the house.
Unbeknownst to either of the owners of the house.
That anything was a skew or was wrong.
On November 13th.
Check number one zero seven four for the amount of $178.53.
It was written on the account.
Here is the Myham Nozarker.
Here is a record of that.
This has been something that we have done for 34 years.
Payment was mail.
To peel box 1288.
Myham Oklahoma.
7 4 35 5 1 2 8 8.
No notice was given.
Is my understanding the the only way that no notice can be given is through a text message that there was anything wrong.
First of the residing in the House, which is still Kim McLean now, we've never had the name change on the bill.
There's not half telecommunications advice to be able to receive text messages.
So, no-nose was given.
It was a surprise that electricity was just shot.
No one came to the door. No one knocked on the door and said, hey, we're shutting electricity off.
The opportunity to come up to the city to try to figure out what was going on.
Obviously, we had expected the federal government and the U.S. Postal Service to deliver that payment in a timely manner,
which it would have been, had they done their job.
We did verify with the bank. At this point, there is the check has not come through for being for anything.
It's a lost check. It happens.
We restore the service on Friday, but in doing so, we're required to pay the reconnect fee, as well as the light payment chart chart.
What I'm asking for is that that light payment chart and that V, be reimbursed, as well as any other fees associated with that.
So, that the bill of 17853, of which you now have funds for, is taken care of.
And I request that from the council.
I can tell you that as people in this community that we've been here for 35 years, that nothing like this has ever happened to.
Thank you.
Five. Climes list.
Much to proof.
Two.
Six.
Minutes from the November 20th, 2023, regular scheduled meeting.
Just two proof.
Second.
Perfect.
Center.
Williams.
Thank you.
Hi.
He's there.
Seven.
The award 2023 annual sewage line.
We're a pair.
The valuation or rehabilitation pill box for wastewater collection system.
MSU-A23-49.
The mayor.
Specialty services LLC is recommended by staff.
Bit based on conceptual work over.
Approved contract.
Contented upon submission.
Of all required contract documents.
An authorized and city manager.
His doesn't need to sign.
Notice to proceed.
As you mentioned, it was a conceptual.
It's early about the only way that you could do a project like this and get all the pricing and everything to come in so you can average it.
Mayor specialty services came in at a million 14947. They were the lowest bidder. You have ace pipe at a million 281 home board 32 and we were hoping to go along with Mayor specialty on it.
And well, this project that it's conceptual, but take them to be the one to went out and we go out to get super room care.
So Tyler is this for you? Can you explain a little bit?
So I'm excited to see a gentleman. So I said to the gentleman I called the two of us that I did up all these in the night. I'm not sure if I could actually 25 pages.
So we are sure staff, so we have an issue that we can harness you and say okay, we do a lot of TV work.
You know, here I see a camera down the sewers. I'm like, I've got to be a lot of people saying well, it is the sewers that the sewers messed up.
Our partner set this up on you. I want you to do it on Friday. So we got a camera there.
It's similar to our, you know, contracts, but we only have one bidder on this.
Well, I see the one we have one.
So explain this conceptual work or something. How did I do it? So they said, okay, we have to compare, you know, apples to apples and they said, okay, you do this.
Okay, you do this make you do TV work and this make you do 20000 points.
But if this may be, you know, man, I'll be lining it up.
So we don't know these guys.
One day and one or two.
It's like a not not to exceed.
Yes, that's not it.
It seems like they've not done a number of career opportunities.
And they said, okay, if you did this much work.
Like we have about six hundred thousand.
Which one do a lot of split line repairs?
That's what they take the sewers on.
So I mean, there's a chance.
And I'm just throwing a number here.
chance this could be 600,000 and over near the 1.1. It's just not going to go.
Yeah, we had to work.
We had to work.
We had to have about that much in that last year.
So we're the 600.
That's part of the one we've experienced for a varsity in our electric.
You know, we start to have money and want to see what we're going to do.
So that's what work order is just doing a starting to pair out with the app.
What was the feedback from Joplin and how they, like what made you decide this was a good idea for the city of Lima?
Just because there's so many different things that they can do to rehab sewers.
So I mean, you know, they, they, they, they, they've got signs that, you know, this theory
I was done by, you know, sales tax with this and that.
And so I'm talking then you can talk to other cities that work and say, hey, what works?
What doesn't work?
So it's kind of like, yeah, I met them on time.
Is it, I just want to be used and really enjoy it.
Who does Joplin use?
I think these days I would say, or one of them, they do that as well.
Where's that mayor out of?
There would be a good idea.
Where?
Good idea.
Got it.
Do they have a crew here?
Or do they have to bring them down each time?
They just bring them down.
Do they have a problem with weak camps and holidays?
And will they use to hasten before?
We've never used this mayor report.
But we haven't been called on their references and some other people that had used it.
Do we still just have one crew?
We have to open anything.
I think somebody retired.
Any other questions?
So what's the, if we don't do this, what does that look like?
What is the, what is it, if we do nothing scenario?
It's always got to, you know what I mean?
If we do this, this is what happens if we do nothing.
What happens?
If we do this, this is what happens.
So the goal here is we're proving infrastructure.
Yes.
And we're doing it according to our budget.
We're using a company that has better equipment and resources.
Yeah.
So what we have, what I look back is, so I need to do that.
We have a variety of answers.
The same areas that we have, you know, the filtration.
And now.
So this is stuff your crew won't be able to get to.
Yeah, it's weak we can't slip line lines.
That's an analogy we do not have, I mean, I'd have to go to that one.
You know, we tried to barge you as you made dollars to have them.
So it's not going to get done unless we do it this way.
Yeah.
You know, and a lot of like, over in the Northeast or in the North West,
because there's not a lot of freedom.
We'd slip line, we don't have to slip line machine.
We don't have to slip line machine.
We don't have to disturb you with jars.
We don't have to disturb the densities.
Make a motion.
We approve.
Second.
All right.
Williams.
Hi.
And go.
Award annual on call concrete repair C23 desperate date.
Cons.
The stress and captain.
Haskell fabrication and construction.
Toro has concrete construction.
Scott construction and needs concrete construction.
But fiscal year 2324.
As recommended by staff approved contracts, continue to upon the submission.
Of all required contract documents and all throughout the city manager.
His does need the sign notice to proceed.
And this one, we do need to do something.
So what I've done, on, did you guys get the two sheets of comparison prices on?
This is all of the different.
This one is in the right.
And the right.
The right.
And once that company gets full and they don't have time.
It could possibly go to the next lowest.
And so.
And it's all over the ward.
You know, some of the ones might be high in one area.
They're a little lower in the other.
But with a, with a pricing sheet like this.
They'll be able to look and go.
Okay.
We have all these projects coming up.
Which one of these would be the most.
And so we need to grant all of them, their all reputable companies, we've dealt with all of them except so what we'd like is for you all to approve going along with them.
So is this for just on-call, concrete repairs, this for total contracts for complete project replacements, like blocks and blocks, or is this intended for repairs, not for total reconstruction?
But this is specified out as annual on-call concrete repair, not contract pricing as far as total street repairs.
So my interpretation of on-call repair is if a waterline breaks and they've got to take out 1,000 square feet of concrete or 1,000 square feet of road.
That's, in order to see on-call repair to have a replace.
So that's what I'm trying to figure out, this is what the city is going to use as a standard for complete street replacement or repairs.
So I guess I'm trying to ask if we're in a way for the city mount project.
Every road we've done in 2023 has been a major project and we've went with these prices that came on this.
And that made nothing up. Because we already had contract pricing for concrete repair.
So I'm trying to figure out if this is a repair price or a total reconstruction price.
So we're getting away from bidding out complete projects.
No? We still made a bit out of complete project. We made a piecemeal project where the city does some of the work and then we contract for some elements of the work.
We'll generally evaluate it and put it together and compare pricing and if we can do piecemeal and get a better deal for the city then that's what we'll do.
So we're not getting away from bidding out that would be something that we'll talk about on some specific projects.
But for the most part, while we've got the resources and we can piecemeal them, that's why we do some...
of those, but that's what we've been meeting with the construction of committee about
and evaluating those projects and kind of go through them.
So I'll track back on track.
I'm just a quick question.
Do we know that by the city doing some of the work and having a contract to do some of the work
that the cities get in the best thing for their butt?
Or is the city able to track what kind of money they're putting in to doing it themselves?
Are they able to track all their labor hours, their trucking hours,
or equipment hours, all of that stuff to where you see if you get a better deal
by the city doing it themselves or hiring someone in at a certain price to do it for you?
Is there a way you guys are tracking?
Yeah.
The numbers that we looked at.
I mean, that's what I've been shown and what the Anderson engineering as came out
and did a study for us and looked at all of our numbers.
And that was what we're being shown is that we get a better deal whenever we piece meal
and use our resources to do it.
And the study that Anderson engineering did was,
that's actually said it's an extraordinary amount of money that we were saving
that the other cities in most cases.
I'm just curious how, what's the actual, what the actual number, what the cities actually saved
by doing the work and stuff.
Which is part of the calculation.
So we had the Anderson too.
Because that's something we're ever going to be able to see.
Because I haven't seen none of it.
We've been meeting with the subcommittee.
We have two councilman since we can't have fire.
We have a forum.
We have two councilman that said on a construction subcommittee
that don't have any conflict with any of the work.
So we've been evaluating it with them and going through it.
And that's the intent is once we are done and have reached the consensus on how we want to go forward,
then we want to present those findings to the entire council.
So Brian, this contract kind of allows us to whatever the circumstances is.
We have a basket of contractors to look at and get our best.
When I got here, I didn't, I didn't understand the way they were doing that.
I thought it was probably one person that was taking care of most of everything.
Excuse me.
But when they explain to me, not having to go out to bed for all of the projects,
we can just do it in a more efficient way.
And stay to go with the lowest bed at the time.
And it makes sense to be in this small community that we have our own.
course, we go to the next best thing to try to get it done quickly for the, you know,
so much. And so, I think it's a really unique way to do it. And it seems like it works well.
How long have we been doing it this way?
Ever since I've been here.
This is not in the summer of year or so.
Doing it this way, do you see the savings? So, when you see the savings, what happens
with the money you say?
I do what?
More, more, more, more.
Thank you.
Sir, what?
I'm just...
I'm just trying to hear it for real.
Two years ago, Brandon would be in full street.
So, if we've been doing this for four or five years, what we did before that, why did we change?
Why did you see a reason to change to this way?
Well, he's gone, we've got a river over here.
So right now, on the current projects you have, do you guys have multiple contractors, foreign streets back?
It's back.
So, thanks for answering my questions.
Appreciate it.
So, by doing this play, you're saying we're saving the citizen's money.
And we're being able to make their dollars go far, they're a picture more street.
I'll make a motion to a group.
Take.
Hi.
Center.
Well, I mean, hold on.
Upstate.
Williams?
Hi.
Double.
You can use that.
Hi.
The ward is six months.
As needed, I ever get C-23-59 to keep stone for fiscal year 23-24.
I'm just breaking it up by staff.
I've got a period contract contingent upon the submission of all required contract documents
and all throughout the city manager.
Or, as does it need to sign?
Notice to proceed.
On this one here, we only have one bitter and it's kept stone.
Supplies with the aggregate.
And that goes to the limestone lateral rock.
And so on.
Did it go up from last year?
It did.
All of these have gone up a little bit.
That was a significant thing that went out.
I had the last.
The price this first one was 1450.
Last.
The last contract that we've had for years.
It was 1350.
It was no dollar.
On that particular one.
The next one.
1375 to 1450.
I mean, yeah.
I mean, they were up about a buck or something.
And that includes hauling.
Yes.
That's that thing.
Did you do the job side?
Or to the barn?
Right.
When you're saying that in the next one, you mean a lot of intent?
Well, the price that I was giving was dropped to jobs.
I was like, right.
But if you want to have it delivered within the city.
It's 1425 and picked up at 775.
We picked it up.
We do all that on the other side.
And that's what this for that panel.
The firm.
Yes.
We have to see it.
We have both of them.
And as needed.
And there's a bigger trust that I've got.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Thank you.
Second.
Hi.
Sir.
Thank you.
Hi.
10 award.
As needed.
Concreate.
Sand.
Supply.
C23-60.
The Muscoe.
Sand.
We're fiscal year.
Approved contract contingent upon the submission of all required contract documents
to authorize city manager or his designated need to sign the notice to proceed.
This one.
We only had one better.
Any was Muscoe.
Sand.
And their price were a ton of delivered.
It's 27.05 now.
The last time.
It was 24.05.
So that was a assignment percentage.
It's pretty good price.
Good.
And what they're increased.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Can't get it.
Jinks or sand springs no more?
I don't know.
Maybe.
But the Muscoe.
Sand.
Yeah.
And that's a pretty good price.
With their increased steel.
Sand.
And they're also good.
So they all have from fairly in two or.
It's an increase.
It's probably not too bad.
Then come and call it.
Let's go.
I don't know.
Some of the salt.
Don't sand.
I hope so.
We don't need a much of it.
I hope you don't need any of this.
Okay.
We have three come.
Two.
Three.
One.
All right.
Alright.
You're welcome.
Eight.
material C-23-61 to NEO concrete and materials.
Prophets per year, 23-24 is recommended by staff.
The proof contract contingent upon the submission of all required contract documents and
author of the city manager, or his debts, need a sign to proceed.
We only had one bitter on this and it was in NEO concrete and material.
We tried some other companies on this thinking that they were going to bid, but NEO was
going on the K-On, the product description on the 3526 on the new bid, the last bid that
we had with the other one, a 130, the last one was 110.
130 is a 4,000.
You might have some knowledge on that one, but if we're good or not, then we'll have to approve
of this too.
Make a motion to approve.
Take it.
Perfect.
Hi.
Cender.
William.
Hi.
He's step.
12.
While the business of me, which is a riddance of the posting of this agenda, 13 staff reports, 14
trustees, meeting announcements, 15 in general.
So moved.
Thank you.
Perfect.
December.
Williams.
Hi.
Thank you.